Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat.
I am
MBA Finance of Founder Family First Financial Services. I have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years and
today I am presenting in front of you that on 6th
February 2024, Life Insurance
Corporation LIC of India has launched a new
unit linked insurance policy by doing
Index Plus, where you will
get growth as per the stock market and you will also get insurance
cover and tax benefit. This
plan is excellent which is index based. Other
companies have or other plans in
which the company has its own funds like
growth fund, balance fund etc. but here
you have index base like NIF 50, in this way
as the index grows, your fund will
also grow. Funds of this type have also been given,
so watch this video completely. If you like the video, then
definitely like, share and
subscribe to my YouTube3FS. Talking about the
entry age of the policy, then a child of 90 days i.e. a
child of 3 months to a person of 60 years can
purchase this policy. Here,
if you pay the premium annually, then
you  You will have to pay a premium of ₹1000000.
If you pay the premium semi-annually i.e. for six months, then
you will have to pay ₹1500000
and in monthly mode you
can pay ₹2500000 premium in this policy for a 90-
day-old child. As I told you, you
can purchase the policy. Talking about
insurance, if your age is from 90 days to
50 years, then you have two options.
You can also take seven times insurance cover or
10 times insurance cover.
But if your age is between 51 to 60, then
you will get seven times insurance cover.
I would recommend that you take 10 times
insurance cover because the
maturity on taking 10 times insurance cover is
tax free. Talking about the
policy term in the policy, if your annual
premium is more than 48000, then you
can take a policy term of 10 years and you
can also take a policy term of up to 25 years. 10 11
12 some  You can also take it, but if you pay a
premium of less than Rs 48,000, then
you will have to take a minimum policy term of 15 years. If we
talk about the premium paying term here, then
you cannot take the regular option of limited pay.
You will have to pay the premium for the number of years of the policy term you have taken,
as
mentioned. You can purchase the policy
in any mode like yearly, quarterly, monthly, semi-annually.
Talking about the
maturity of the policy, if you have taken seven times the
insurance cover, then you
can run this policy till the age of 85 and if you have
taken 10 times the insurance cover, then the
maturity age will be maximum up to 75 years.
Talking about the minimum maturity of the vesting age of the policy, it should be
18 years or the
vesting age is also 18 years. In this
policy, when we talk about the death benefit in the policy, then the death benefit is given to you in a
unit linked policy, then
you get the higher of the fund value or your insurance cover, minus if any partial
withdrawal has been done in the last two years, then
that partial withdrawal will be given.  Withdrawal is reduced from it,
but the good thing is that
partial withdrawal is counted only for 24 months,
after that your basic
method is restored, for example, your insurance
cover was ₹ lakh, suppose you had ₹ lakh, then you can withdraw from your fund,
but as soon as 2 years are completed,
your insurance will again become 10 lakh,
so the maturity benefit is the
fund value in unit thing insurance policies,
your fund grows according to the market, according to that
you
get maturity in the policy, refund of mortality
charges also in this policy, the charges which are levied on your insurance,
which are
called mortality charges, will be refunded to
you along with the maturity of the policy,
these will also be refunded at the end of the policy,
but the good thing is that the mortality charges
which are levied in this product of LIC are levied
on sum at risk, sum at risk
means that suppose your insurance cover is
₹10 lakh. According to the market, your fund
grows to ₹10 lakh, so 10 lakh minus 5
lakh means you have to pay mortality charges only on the remaining 5 lakh.
Now suppose
your fund grows to ₹000, then
your mortality charges will become zero.
You are also given guaranteed additions in the policy,
this can be called a kind of loyalty benefit. The
longer you
remain in the policy, you are given an extra benefit
in this fund of LIC, which is
known as guaranteed addition. For example,
suppose you are paying a premium of ₹1 lakh, then every
year
% of your premium of Rs 1 lakh, 000 will be
added to your fund value.
10000 will be added in the 2nd year, 20000 in the 15th year,
25000 in the 20th year and 0000 in the 25th year will be added to
your fund as a guaranteed addition.  Age in value: Call it loyalty
benefit because if you stay with the company for a long time, the
company
gives you extra money. As a guaranteed addition,
accidental death benefit rider
is also available. If you want to
increase your insurance cover a little,
you can opt for this rider. Minors
cannot take this rider. Majors who are 18
years of age or above can
add accidental death rider.
You can add this rider anytime in the policy term
except the last 5 years.
Withdrawal: Just like in a traditional policy,
when you need money,
you have to take a loan, but this policy has the
facility that you can withdraw money even without taking a loan. There is
liquidity. You
cannot do this partial withdrawal if you are a minor, but
if your age exceeds 18 years or
you are already above 18 years, then
you get the facility of partial withdrawal.
How much can you withdraw? For example, your
policy term is from six years.
If you want to withdraw money in the middle of the 10th year, then
your fund value is, suppose you were paying a premium of ₹1 lakh,
in 10 years you
paid ₹10 lakh, according to the market your amount became ₹
1 lakh, then you can withdraw the fund value up to ₹15 lakh at 20, you do
not have to pay it back without taking a loan, if the policy term is 11 to 15 years,
then you can withdraw the money at 25, between 16 to 20 years
you can withdraw at 30 and between 21 to 25 years
you can withdraw the money up to your fund value at 35,
but you also have to keep in
mind that if your premium
is less than ₹48000 then you will have to keep the
fund value equal to four premiums always and
if your premium is more than ₹48000 then you will have to keep the money
equal to three premiums in this policy,
you can withdraw the remaining amount,
talk about switching benefit in the policy,
suppose you have
selected any one of the two funds and in future you
feel that I  If you want to switch from this fund to another fund,
you can switch free
of cost four times in a year. You can switch four times in a year,
that too without any fee. Switching
from one fund to another is
called switching. We talk about the
investment of the fund, the entire plan, any
unit-linked policy. If you are purchasing,
buy the policy of any company. The most
important thing is the investment of the fund.
Every company has different funds in a single policy.
Everyone's performance is
different, everyone's returns are different. So
your entire maturity depends on the fund performance. So,
you are given two funds in this policy. The
name of the first fund is Flexi Growth Fund and the
name of the second fund is Flexi Smart
Growth Fund. If you take Flexi Growth Fund, then
your money will be
invested in Nifty 100 Index Fund. And if you
take Flexi Smart Growth Fund, then
your money will be invested in NSC Nifty 50. So,
according to which index will your
investment be and which fund to take,
you can see this in this.  Suppose you
take a Flexi Growth Fund, then here
your money from zero to 20% will be
invested in government securities. You can invest in corporate bonds.
Your fund manager can
invest from zero to 40% in short-term investments or money markets.
And in equities,
your investment will be from 40% to 100%. The minimum
40% will always be in equities. If the
fund manager feels that the equity
portion needs to be increased, he can invest up to 100%
in equities.
Similarly, there will be a Flexi Smart Growth Fund.
These are high-risk, high-return
products. If you see the risk
profile, it is written as very high risk,
meaning this plan is for those who
want to see returns by taking risks and who
focus more on returns.
This is a high-risk, high-return product. So,
you can select which fund you want to buy. If
you want to change it in the future,
you can also change it through switching.
Now let's understand both these
funds.  In which companies do you
invest? Let us see
now the two funds
given in this policy. For example, if we talk about Ni 100,
which companies are there in it, like you
will see FC Limited
itself, LIC of India, State
Bank of India, Indian Oil, Bharat
Petroleum, Canada Bank, you will see
Power Bid, Bank of Baroda, Tomato, Varun,
Tata Power, Bharat
Electronics, Ko India, ACL,
Bajaj, Tata Consultancy, Punjab National
Bank, all these top companies,
your money will be invested in them.
Apart from that, if you see that if you select another fund
in Nifty 50, then
if you look at Nifty 50, the biggest
contributor is State Bank of India,
Bharat Petroleum, Power Bid, Ko
India, ACL, Tata Consultancy,
LCO, Bajaj Auto, etc. So in this way,
your money will be invested in multiple companies
by the fund manager and you will
get returns according to the fund performance of the
funds you select.
You will get returns from that, so a
small amount will be invested in so many companies,
so I will explain this benefit illustration
in detail, as per the IID nom,
which is illustration 4 and as per the table at 8,
I will tell how much
return you will get, the actual returns can be more
or less than this, what are the charges etc.,
you will be able to know about that in detail in this benefit illustration,
how you will get
guaranteed addition, you will be able to
understand that also in this benefit illustration, let us
see, now let us understand the benefit
illustration, the new product launched by LIC
is LIC Index Fund, which is a unit
linked insurance policy, which neither
participates in bonus nor is guaranteed, this
equity based product will be for you, let us
consider an example here, a 35 year old person is
purchasing a policy in which he will pay
premium for 20 years and is
using that policy for 20 years only, which will be
his insurance cover and he has invested in
GF which is high ha va pr  It will keep on taking it but
now I will
not have to pay it but now you will have to pay it and
you will have to pay it but there may be a difference, it may be
more also, but the
past history shows that the fund
performance will be quite good, if we
look at the fund performance of NEC currently also, the
return is being given at 15-16% of equity, so it will depend
on the share market, this fund fund
performance, but on this edge, the
illustration table which has to be mentioned mandatory, is
mentioned in front of you at % and 4, where charges etc. are also
mentioned in details, as I am
telling you, according to the % table, let us understand
that if you are paying
lakhs, you are paying premium for 20 years,
where you will pay premium for the first year,
then you will pay 5% for the
next 4 years, then at 4, there
is premium allocation, after deducting the local charges,
how much will your money be, after that the
insurance of Motihari charge, but the good thing is Motihari
charge means after deducting 5% from the amount cover, you
will see the remaining amount, you will see it in column number 15 of the fund, as soon as
If the result becomes one lakh then
your mop will become zero, hence
mop will keep decreasing every year and
you will also get this mop back in the app.
Apart from this, the guarantee addition that you get will keep
increasing and from now onwards
you will get more money every year [Music], whether it is more or less, the more money is
more.
Now
you will get more in a year.
India is doing it in this way, so this
benefit
comes to people, think about it, let's
talk about other features of this policy,
here the date of vesting i.e.
after 18 years, you get the date of vesting. If we
talk about income tax benefit, then
you will get the benefit of ATC here and
also the benefit of 10D. So, if
you invest up to Rs 1 lakh in ULIP under Indian law, then the maturity
on it is
tax free.
If a person invests more than Rs 1 lakh,
then you have to pay taxes. If we talk about the
loan in this policy, then it is a unit link
insurance policy, so there is facility of loan in it.  There is
also a revival period of three years in the policy, if for some reason
you are not able to pay the premium on time, then
you can revive the policy for 3 years by paying the remaining premiums together and
can continue it. Talking about
top up in the policy, there is no
top up facility available in this policy.
Premium allocation here is 8% in the first year,
55% between the second and fifth year
and 4% thereafter.
Mortality charges: The younger you are, the
more I would recommend purchasing this policy.
Charges are a little higher on higher rates. For example, if
you
purchase insurance for Rs. 000 and your age is 25 years, then you will have to pay Rs
.  Your mortality charges are ₹26 only,
but if you are 60 years old, then
above ₹1000,
you will get ₹1.35 in both the funds. The
fund manager who
manages your fund charges a fee. If we
talk about surrender in the policy, then after
five years, the lock-in period is five years.
After five years, you
can surrender this policy and can also take the entire money.
If you do not want to surrender, then
you already have the facility of parcel withdrawal.
Talking about the free period,
if you want to cancel the policy due to any reason, then 30
days time has been given in this policy that
you can go to the LIC office and submit the policy bond
and
tell the reason for cancellation and you can cancel the policy.
This free fund will be available to you for 30 days.
If I compare this policy, then
this is an excellent product of LIC where
your money is going into two funds which are
index based funds.  And
if we look at the past performance of LIC's ULIP, if we
look at the fund performance, then the fund
performance is quite good. If we talk about the age of now, February 2024, then the
shares of LIC have also
gone above 1100, which at one time were around 500, so the
shares of LIC are also growing very well, the
funds are also growing very well
and both these funds are also very
good, they are in the initial stage, so
you will get very low NVP
and you are also getting tax benefits, you also have the
benefit of riders,
you have also been given the facility of withdrawing parcel money
in this plan, so if you want to purchase this policy from me, then you
can contact me on my mobile number 99403 3412.
If you like my video, then you will
already find more than 2 videos of mine on YouTube,
where
those videos will help you in doing your financial planning.
Thank you so much, Jai
Hind